嘿，TAS将就并发性进行演讲，并且基本上
hey the TAS are going to be giving a
lecture on concurrency and go basically
本讲座将充满设计模式和实用技巧，
this lecture is going to be full of
design patterns and practical tips to
帮助您进行实验，我们将简要介绍代码存储模型
help you with the labs we're going to be
covering briefly the code memory model
我们读完之后的阅读，然后大部分的演讲都在谈论
the reading which we went over and then
spend most of the lecture talking about
并发原语，并发模式，以及如何做
concurrency primitives and go
concurrency patterns and go how you do
您需要在实验室中做的事情，然后最后我们将讨论
things that you will need to do in the
labs and then finally we'll talk through
一些调试技巧和技术，并向您展示一些有趣的工具
some debugging tips and techniques and
show you some interesting tools that you
可能想在调试实验室时使用，因此在运行中非常简短地使用内存
might want to use when debugging the
labs so very briefly on the go memory
以读数为模型，为什么我们要很好地分配此读数，目标是
model on the reading so why did we
assign this reading well the goal was to
给您一些编写线程代码的正确方法的具体示例，以及
give you some concrete examples of
correct ways to write threaded code and
因此，像文档后半部分中的文档中有一些示例
go so the document like in the second
half of the document has some examples
破解代码和不正确的代码以及它可能如何出错所以一件事
of crack code and an incorrect code and
how it can go wrong so one thing you
可能已经在文档的早期注意到它说如果您需要阅读和
might have noticed in the document is
early on it says if you need to read and
了解这一点，您太聪明了，我们认为这是个好建议，因此
understand this you're being too clever
and we think that that's good advice so
专注于如何编写正确的代码，不要过多地关注之前发生的事情
focus on how to write correct code don't
focus way too much on the happens before
关系并能够推理出为什么不正确的代码不正确
relation and being able to reason about
exactly why incorrect code is incorrect
就像我们不在乎，我们只想能够编写正确的代码，
like we don't really care we just want
to be able to write correct code and
称它为一天讲课中出现的一个问题
call it a day
one question that came up in the lecture
问题就像谈论与性能相关的goroutines
questions was like talking about
goroutines in relation to performance
所以我们只想说goroutine和一般
and so we just wanted to say that
goroutines and like in general
并发有多种不同的原因，而我们使用的原因
concurrency can be used for a couple
different reasons and the reason we use
实验室中的并发并不一定像我们
concurrency in the labs is not
necessarily for performance like we're
不要在单台机器上使用多个内核进行并行处理
not going for parallelism using multiple
cores on a single machine in order to be
能够在CPU并发性上做更多的工作为我们带来了其他好处
able to do more work on the CPU
concurrency gets us something else
除了通过并行性实现性能之外，它还可以使我们成为更好的专家Civet ii
besides performance through parallelism
it can get us better expert Civet ii
就像我们想写下一些想法，恰好是写下来
like we want to write down some ideas
and it happens to be that writing down
使用线程的代码是表达这些想法的一种干净方法，因此
code that uses threads is a clean way of
expressing those ideas and so the
得出的结论是，当您在实验2和更高版本中使用线程时，请勿尝试
takeaway from that is when you use
threads in lab 2 and Beyond don't try to
做一些您想提高性能（特别是CPU）时可能要做的事情
do fancy things you might do if you're
going for performance especially CPU
像我们不关心做的事情，例如使用细粒度锁定
performance like we don't care to do
things like using fine-grained locking
或其他技术基本上使用了易于使用的代码
or other techniques use basically write
code that's easy to reason about use big
锁来保护较大的关键部分，就像不用担心
locks to protect large critical sections
and just like don't worry about
CPU性能意义上的性能
performance in the sense of CPU
performance
这就是我们要说的有关内存模型和花费的全部信息
so with that that's all we're going to
say about the memory model and spend
本讲座的大部分内容仅讨论go代码和并发模式，以及
most of this lecture just talking about
go code and go concurrency patterns and
当我们浏览这些示例时，请随时询问有关什么是什么的任何问题。
as we go through these examples feel
free to ask any questions about what's
在屏幕上或您可能会想到的其他任何东西上，所以我将开始
on the screen or anything else you might
think about so I'm going to start off
谈论并发原语，所以首先要做的是关闭
talking about concurrency primitives and
go so the first thing is closures this
在实验室中几乎肯定会有帮助，这是
is something that will almost certainly
be helpful in the labs and this is
与go例程相关，所以这是屏幕上的示例程序，以及
related to go routines so here's this
example program on the screen and what
它确实是主函数声明了一堆变量，然后产生这个变量
it does is the main function declares a
bunch of variables and then spawns this
使用go语句在这里进行例行检查，我们注意到得分
go routine in here with this go
statement and we noticed that the score
例程不将其作为参数调用定义的某些函数
routine is not taking it as an argument
a function call to some function defined
其他地方，但是这个匿名函数只是在这里定义的，所以这是一个
elsewhere but this anonymous function
just defined in line here so this is a
方便的模式，这被称为闭包，与此有关的一件整洁的事情是
handy pattern this is something called a
closure and one neat thing about this is
此处定义的函数可以引用来自
that this function that's defined here
can refer to variables from the
封闭范围，例如，此功能可以使该变量
enclosing scope so for example this
function can mutate this variable a
是在这里定义的，或者是在这里定义的这个体重组
that's defined up here or refer to this
weight group that's defined up here so
如果我们运行此示例，它会执行您认为的操作
if we go run this example it does what
you think it does
重量组点在这里完成让我们继续主线程到此为止
the weight group dot done here let's the
main thread continue past this point it
打印出该变量，该变量已被并发运行
prints out this variable which has been
mutated by this concurrently running
在此重量发生之前完成的线程，因此这是一种有用的模式
thread that finished before this weight
happened so this is a useful pattern to
能够像我们这样指出的原因是因为您可能
be able to use one like the reason we're
pointing this out is because you might
在您的实验室中具有类似于以下代码的代码
have code that looks like this in your
labs very similar to the previous
例子，除了这是在循环中产生一堆线程的代码
example except this is code that is
spawning a bunch of threads in a loop
例如，这在您要并行发送我们的个人计算机时非常有用
this is useful for example when you want
to send our pcs in parallel right so
就像在实验二中，如果您有候选人要投票
like in lab two if you have a candidate
asking for votes you want to ask for
来自所有关注者的并行投票，而不是一个又一个的投票，因为RPC
votes from all the followers in parallel
not one after the other because the RPC
是一项封锁作业，可能需要一些时间，或者类似的领导者可能
is a blocking operation that might take
some time or similarly the leader might
希望将附加条目发送给要并行执行的所有关注者
want to send append entries to all the
followers you want to do it in parallel
不是串联的，所以线程是表达此想法的一种干净方法，因此您
not in series and so threads are a clean
way to express this idea and so you
在for循环中，您的代码可能看起来像这样
might have code that looks kind of like
this at a high level in a for loop you
产生一堆go例程这里要注意的一件事是
spawn a bunch of go routines one thing
to be careful about here this is
在上一讲中已经讨论过的东西
something that was talked about in a
previous lecture
是标识符捕获，goroutines和外部标识符的突变
is identifier capture and goroutines and
mutation of that identifier in the outer
范围，所以我们在这里看到我们的眼睛被这个突变了
scope so we see here that we have this
eye that's being mutated by this for
循环，然后我们想在平方根和方法中使用该值
loop and then we want to use that value
inside the square root een and the way
我们这样做就像编写此代码的正确方法是传递此值
we do that like the correct way of
writing this code is to pass this value
我作为该函数和该函数的参数，也可以将其重命名为X
I as an argument to this function and
this function or you can rename it to X
在这里，然后使用里面的值，所以如果我们运行此程序
inside here and then use the value
inside and so if we run this program
所以在这里我有点想发送PC的东西实际上只是打印的东西
so here I've kind of stubbed out to send
our PC thing was actually just prints
出来的索引，我可能就像跟随者尝试发送一个索引的索引
out the index this I might be like the
index of the follower trying to send an
RPC到这里以某种顺序打印数字0到4，所以这就是
RPC to here prints out the numbers 0
through 4 in some order so this is what
我们希望像将PC发送给所有关注者那样，向我们展示您的原因
we want like send our PCs to all the
followers the reason we're showing you
这段代码是因为这段代码有些变化，看起来非常相似
this code is because there's a variation
of this code which looks really similar
也许直觉上您可能会认为它做对了，但实际上
and maybe intuitively you might think it
does the right thing but in fact it
并非如此，在此代码中唯一更改的是我们摆脱了
doesn't so in this code the only thing
that's changed is we've gotten rid of
在这里，我们明确地传递了这个论点，相反，我们让我
this argument here that we're explicitly
passing and instead we're letting this I
从外部观察镜指向眼睛，所以您可能会认为
refer to the eye from the outer scope so
you might think that when you run this
它执行相同的操作，但实际上在此特定运行中它已打印4 5 5 5 5
it does the same thing but in fact in
this particular run it printed 4 5 5 5 5
所以这样做会做错事，原因是我正在
so this would do the wrong thing and the
reason for this is that this I is being
被这个外部范围和这个go例程实际结束的时间所改变
mutated by this outer scope and by the
time this go routine ends up actually
很好地执行此行，for循环已经更改了I的值，因此
executing this line well the for loop
has already changed the value of I so
这不会做正确的事情，因此，如果您正在生成goroutine，那么在较高的层次上
this doesn't do the right thing so at a
high level if you're spawning goroutines
只需确保在此处使用此模式，一切都会
in a loop just make sure that you use
this pattern here and everything will
处理有关此问题的任何问题，所以就像一个小陷阱，但是
work right any questions about that
so it's just like a small gotcha but
我们在办公时间内已经看过很多次了，所以我只想
we've seen this a whole bunch of times
in office hours so I just wanted to
指出这一点没关系，所以转到其他可能需要的模式
point this out all right so moving on to
other patterns that you might want to
经常在您的代码中使用您想要定期执行某项操作的代码
use in your code oftentimes you want
code that periodically does something a
一种非常简单的方法是拥有一个无限的独立函数
very simple way to do that is to have a
separate function that in an infinite
在这种情况下，循环会执行某些操作，我们只是打印出刻度，然后使用它
loop does something in this case we're
just printing out tick and then use this
时间点睡眠，等待一定的时间，所以非常简单的模式
time dot sleep to wait for a certain
amount of time so very simple pattern
在这里，您不需要任何比
here
you don't need anything fancier than
定期做某事
this to do something periodically
您可能想要的一种修改是您想要做某事
one modification of this that you might
want is you want to do something
定期直到发生某件事，例如您可能要启动一个
periodically until something happens for
example you might want to start up a
在这里漂流，然后定期发送心跳，但是当我们将点击
raft here and then periodically send
heartbeats but when we call dot kill on
您要实际关闭所有这些goroutine的筏实例，因此您
the raft instance you want to actually
shut down all these goroutines so you
不要让所有这些随机goroutine仍在后台运行，因此
don't have all these random goroutines
still running in the background and so
模式看起来像这样，您有一个goroutine，它将
the pattern for that looks something
like this you have a goroutine that will
无限循环运行并执行某些操作，然后稍等片刻，然后
run in an infinite loop and do something
and then wait for a little bit and then
您可以在任何控制线程之间共享一个共享变量
you can just have a shared variable
between whatever control thread is going
决定这个goroutine是否应该死，所以在这个例子中
to decide whether this goroutine should
die or not so in this example we have
这个变量完成了，这是一个全局变量，主要是等待
this variable done that's a global
variable and what main does is it waits
一会儿，并完成设置为true，在此例行程序中
for awhile and sets done to true and in
this go routine that's ticking and doing
定期工作，我们只是检查完成的值，如果完成设置
work periodically we're just checking
the value of done and if done is set
然后我们终止平方根eeen，因为完成是共享变量
then we terminate the square-root eeen
and here since done is a shared variable
被多个线程变异并读取时，我们需要确保
being mutated and read by multiple
threads we need to make sure that we
用锁保护它的使用，以便该静音不法分子可以将其静音
guard the use of this with a lock so
that's where this mute outlaw can mute
它解锁是出于您实际可以编写的实验目的
it unlock comes in for the purpose of
the labs you can actually write
比这简单一些的东西，所以我们在您的射频上杀死了这种方法
something a little bit simpler than this
so we have this method RF killed on your
筏实例，所以您可能会有看起来像这样的代码
raft instance so you might have code
that looks a little bit more like this
所以当您被包裹时，实例还没死，您想定期做一些
so while you're wrapped instance is not
dead you want to periodically do some
处理到目前为止的任何问题，是的
work any questions about that so far
yeah question
确实使用了通道的锁定机制使得它可以
does using the locking mechanisms for
channels make it so that any right
阻碍任何变量，并且击剑运动员将观察到那些功能
stunts any variables and those functions
are to be observed by the fencer would
您需要跨渠道发送完成
you need to send done across the channel
好吧，让我尝试简化一下问题，我认为问题是
okay so let me try to simplify the
question a bit I think the question is
您需要在这里使用锁吗？您可以改用通道吗？
do you need to use locks here can you
use channels instead and R and can you
不使用锁而逃脱，就像什么之间没有什么区别
get away with not using locks and like
what's the difference between nothing
与通道与锁的对比，基本上是您要问的，我认为
versus channels vs locks is that
basically what you're asking I think the
问题是这样做完成了吗，不需要跨通道发送吗
question is this done does it not need
to be sent across a channel does just
使用这些锁确保此处的读取遵守线程执行的写入
using these locks ensure that this read
here observes the write done by a thread
好吧，如果您想确保交叉，答案基本上是肯定的
okay so the answer is yes basically at a
high level if you want to ensure cross
线程通信确保您使用go同步原语
thread communication make sure you use
go synchronization primitives whether
它是通道或锁以及条件变量，因此在这里由于使用
it's channels or locks and condition
variables and so here because of the use
此线程写入完成后，并解锁下一个锁
of locks after this thread writes done
and does unlock the next lock that
发生的情况可以确保在此之前观察之前完成的写入
happens is guaranteed to observe the
writes done before that before this
解锁发生了，所以您发生了写入，然后发生了解锁
unlock happened so you have this write
happened and this unlock happened then
这些锁之一发生，然后保证可以完成下一个
one of these locks happens and then the
next done will be guaranteed to observe
真正的问题
that write of true question
在这个特定的代码中，这是一个很好的问题，没关系，但是
that's a good question in this
particular code it doesn't matter but it
这样做会更清洁，所以问题是为什么我们不这样做
would be cleaner to do it so the
question is why don't we do mu dot
返回之前在这里解锁，答案就在这里，再也不会像
unlock here before returning and the
answer is in here there's no more like
该程序已完成，因此实际上并不重要，但是您
the program's done so it doesn't
actually end up mattering but you're
对，就像我们一般希望确保在我们解锁之前
right that like in general we would want
to ensure that we unlock before we
返回是的，谢谢指出
return yeah thanks for pointing that out
所以我不能完全确定问题是什么，但也许可以
so I'm not sure entirely what the
question is but maybe something like can
这两个都同时获得了锁，是这个问题，我们将
both of these acquire the lock at the
same time is that the question and we'll
稍等片刻，然后在更高层次上更多地讨论锁
talk a little bit more about locks in
just a moment but at a high level the
锁的语义是该锁是由某人持有还是不由某人持有
semantics of a lock are the lock is
either held by somebody or not held by
某人，如果不是某人持有，则有人呼叫锁定他们
somebody and if it's not held by
somebody then if someone calls lock they
有机会获得锁，如果他们在打电话之前解锁了其他人
have the chance to acquire the lock and
if before they call unlock somebody else
调用锁定其他线程将被阻塞，直到解锁发生，然后
calls lock that other thread is going to
be blocked until the unlock happens then
锁又是自由的，因此在锁和解锁之间处于较高的水平
the lock is free again so at a high
level between the lock and the unlock
对于任何特定的锁，例如只有一个线程可以执行的锁
for any particular lock like any only a
single thread can be executing what's
称为锁定和解锁区域之间的任何其他关键区域
called a critical section between the
lock and unlock regions any other
问题
questions
因此，问题与计时相关，例如您将完成设置为true时，
so the question is related to timing
like when you set done equals true and
那么您就无法像实时的那样解锁实时性
then you unlock you have no guarantee in
terms of real time like when periodic
将最终被安排并遵守此权利，并最终
will end up being scheduled and observe
this right and actually end up
终止，所以是的，如果您想真正确保定期
terminating and so yes if you want to
mean to actually ensure that periodic
已经出于某些特定原因退出了，那么您可以编写一些代码
has exited for some particular reason
then you could write some code that
从定期确认回传，但在此
communicates back from periodic
acknowledging this but in this
就像我们在这里睡觉的唯一原因那样的特殊情况
particular case like the only reason we
have the sleep here is just to
证明这里的睡眠只是为了证明tick的打印
demonstrate that the sleep here is just
to demonstrate that tick prints for a
然后定期取消它，因为它在之前停止打印
while and then periodic as indeed cancel
it because it stops being printed before
我得到了我的shell提示，通常来说，这些背景很多
I get my shell prompt back and in
general for a lot of these background
像您这样的线程只能说您想杀死它们，没关系
threads like you can just say that you
want to kill them and it doesn't matter
如果他们在1秒钟或2秒内被杀死，或者准确地说是
if they're killed within 1 second or
within 2 seconds or one exactly go
安排它，因为此线程将仅遵守此完成权
schedules it because this thread is
going to just observe this right to done
然后退出，不再执行任何操作，这并不重要，另外
and then exit do no more works it
doesn't really matter and also another
进行中的事情是，如果您生成了一堆goo例程，则其中一个是主要的
thing in go is that if you spawn a bunch
of goo routines one of them is the main
在这里进行例行检查，方法是，如果主要的例行检查
go routine this one here and the way go
works is that if the main goroutine
退出，整个程序终止，所有执行例程终止
exits the whole program terminates and
all go routines are terminated
这是一个很好的问题，所以我认为问题就像是为什么
that's a great question okay so I think
the question is something like why do
您根本需要锁，就像可以删除所有锁，然后喜欢
you need locks at all like can you just
delete all the locks and then like
看这段代码，看起来好吧main在某个时候做了对的权利
looking at this code it looks like okay
main does a right to true at some point
定期重复阅读它，因此在某个时候应该观察到这一点
and periodic is repeatedly reading it so
at some point it should observe this
读得好，事实证明，这就是为什么要去拥有这种奇特的记忆
read right well it turns out that like
this is why go has this fancy memory
模型，您就可以在联系之前进行所有操作
model and you have this whole thing on
that happens before relation the
允许编译器采用此代码并发出一种低级计算机
compiler is allowed to take this code
and emit a kind of low-level machine
所做的代码与您的直觉代码有所不同
code that does something a little bit
different than what you intuitively
想法会在这里发生，之后我们可以离线详细讨论
thought would happen here and we can
talk about that in detail offline after
上课和上课时间，但总的来说，我认为你可以
the lecture and office hours but at a
high level I think one rule you can
如果您有权访问共享变量，并且希望能够
follow is if you have accesses to shared
variables and you want to be able to
跨不同线程观察它们，您需要先保持锁定
observe them across different threads
you need to be holding a lock before you
在这种情况下，我可以读取或写入这些共享变量
read or write those shared variables in
this particular case I think the go
将允许编译器对此进行优化，以提升完成的读取率
compiler would be allowed to optimize
this to like lift the read of done
在四个之外，因此请一次读取此共享变量，如果完成则为false
outside the four so read this shared
variable once and then if done is false
然后设置像使内部成为无限循环，因为像现在这样
then set like make the inside be an
infinite loop because like now the way
这个线程是写的，它没有使用同步原语，没有
this thread is written it had uses no
synchronization primitives there's no
互斥锁锁定或解锁没有通道发送或接收，因此实际上不是
mutex lock or unlock no channel sends or
receives and so it's actually not
保证观察到其他同时运行的线程所做的任何变异
guaranteed to observe any mutations done
by other concurrently running threads
如果您看广场，我实际上喜欢编写一个特定的go程序
and if you look on Piazza I've actually
like written a particular go program
以非直观的方式进行了优化，例如它将生成执行以下操作的代码：
that is optimized in the unintuitive way
like it'll produce code that does an
无限循环，即使您看起来像它一样，您可能会认为
infinite loop even though looking at it
like you might think that oh the obvious
编译此代码的方式会产生某些终止的信息，因此
way to compile this code will produce
something that terminates yeah so the
内存模型非常漂亮，很难思考为什么
memory model is pretty fancy and it's
really hard to think about why exactly
错误的程序是错误的，但是如果您遵循一些通用规则，例如
incorrect programs are incorrect but if
you follow some general rules like whole
在更改共享变量之前先进行阻塞，然后您可以避免思考
blocks before you mutate shared
variables then you can avoid thinking
关于这些令人讨厌的问题
about some of these nasty issues
任何其他问题都好，让我们现在再讨论一下互斥锁
any other questions all right so let's
talk a little bit more about mutexes now
所以为什么每当有并发请求时，互斥量都很高
so why do you need mutex is at a high
level whenever you have concurrent
通过不同的线程访问某些共享数据，以确保
access but by different threads to some
shared data you want to ensure that
该数据的读取和写入是原子的，因此这是程序的一个示例，
reads and writes of that data are atomic
so here's one example of program that
声明一个计数器，然后产生一个goroutine
declares a counter and then spawns a
goroutine
实际上会产生一千个go例程，每个例程都会更新计数器值，
actually spawns a thousand go routines
that each update the counter value and
将其增加一个，您可能会认为当我
increment it by one and you might think
that looking at this intuitively when I
最后打印出计数器的值，它应该打印一千，但是
print out the value of the counter at
the end it should print a thousand but
事实证明，在这种情况下，我们错过了一些更新
it turns out that we missed some of the
updates here and in this particular case
它只打印了947，所以这里发生的是此更新不是
it only printed 947 so what's going on
here is that this update here is not
受到任何方式的真正保护，因此这些同时运行的线程可以读取
really protected in any way and so these
threads running concurrently can read
计数器的值并更新它和破坏其他线程的更新
the value of counter and update it and
clobber other threads updates of this
像基本上这样的值，我们要确保这里的整个部分都发生
value like basically we want to ensure
that this entire section here happens
因此，使代码块自动运行的方式是
atomically and so the way you make
blocks of code run atomically are by
使用锁，因此在此代码示例中，我们修复了此错误，我们创建了一个锁
using locks and so in this code example
we've fixed this bug we create a lock
然后所有这些修改该计数器值的go例程都首先抢占了
and then all these go routines that
modify this counter value first grab the
锁定，然后更新计数器值，然后解锁，我们看到我们正在使用
lock then update the counter value and
then unlock and we see that we're using
这个defer关键字在这里的作用与将其放置的基本相同
this defer keyword here what this does
is basically the same as putting this
代码在这里，所以我们抓住一个锁进行一些更新，然后解锁延后只是一个不错的选择
code down here so we grab a lock do some
update then unlock defer is just a nice
记住这样做的方式，您可能会忘记以后写解锁，因此
way of remembering to do this you might
forget to write the unlock later and so
defer所做的是，您可以将其视为计划将其运行在
what defer does is it you can think of
it as like scheduling this to run at the
当前函数体的结尾，所以这是一个非常常见的模式
end of the current function body and so
this is a really common pattern you'll
例如在实验室的RPC处理程序中查看，因此RPC处理程序通常会
see for example in your RPC handlers for
the lab so oftentimes RPC handlers will
在RAF结构和其他结构上操纵读写数据
manipulate either read or write data on
the RAF structure right and those
更新应与其他同时发生的更新同步，并且
所以通常RPC句柄的模式就像抢锁
so oftentimes the pattern for RPC
handles would be like grab the lock
不同的解锁，然后在内部做一些工作，以便我们可以查看是否运行此代码
differ unlock and then go do some work
inside so we can see if we run this code
它产生了预期的结果，所以它打印出一千，而我们还没有
it produces the expected results so it
prints out a thousand and we haven't
丢失了这些更新中的任何一个，因此在较高级别上锁或互斥锁可以做什么
lost any of these updates and so what at
a high level what a lock or a mutex can
这样做是为了确保在我们称为关键代码区域内相互排斥
do is guarantee mutual exclusion for a
region of code which we call a critical
部分，因此在这里这是关键部分，它可以确保
section so in here this is the critical
section and it ensures that none of
这些关键部分与
these critical sections execute
concurrently with
他们都被序列化的问题一个接一个地发生
ones they're all serialized happened one
after another question
是的，所以这是一个很好的观察，但实际上不是
yes so this is a good observation this
particular could is actually not
保证产生一千个取决于线程调度如何结束
guaranteed to produce a thousand
depending on how thread scheduling end
最终会发生，因为青少年的平均意思是等待一个
up ends up happening because all the
mean guru teen does is it waits for one
秒，它是任意时间单位，然后打印出
second which is some arbitrary unit of
time and then it prints out the value of
计数器，我只想让这个例子尽可能简单
the counter I just want to keep this
example as simple as possible a
不同的方式来编写此代码，可以保证打印出一千
different way to write this code that
would be guaranteed to print a thousand
将使主要goroutine等待所有这千个线程完成
would be to have the main goroutine wait
for all these thousand threads to finish
因此您可以使用权重组进行此操作，但我们不想
so you could do this using a weight
group for example but we didn't want to
将两个同步原语（例如权重组和互斥体）放在同一位置
put two synchronization primitives like
weight groups and mutex is in the same
示例，这就是为什么我们使用此代码在技术上是不正确的，但是我
example so that's why we're at this code
that is like technically incorrect but I
认为它仍然显示出锁定其他任何问题的观点，因此
think it still demonstrates the point of
locks any other questions great so at a
您可以想到的锁级别很高，就像您抓住了变异的锁一样
very high level you can think of locks
is like you grab the lock you mutate the
共享数据，然后您将其解锁，因此此模式始终可以正常工作
shared data and then you unlock so does
this pattern always work well turns out
这就像是思考锁的有用起点，但是
that that's like a useful starting point
for how to think about locks but it's
并不是完整的故事，所以这是一些不适合屏幕显示的代码
not really the complete story so here's
some code this doesn't fit on the screen
但我会向您解释，我们可以滚动浏览它基本上实现了
but I'll explain it to you we can scroll
through it it basically implements a
高水平的银行，所以我有爱丽丝和鲍勃，他们都从一些
bank at a high level so I have Alice and
Bob who both start out with some
余额，然后我跟踪总余额（例如总金额）是多少
balances and then I keep track of what
the total balances like the total amount
存入我的银行的钱，然后我将去做一些日常工作
of money I store in my bank and then I'm
going to spawn to go routines that will
在我们的爱丽丝和鲍勃之间来回转账，所以这个女孩
transfer money back and forth between
our Alice and Bob so this one girl
例行程序，一千次将减少爱丽丝的一遍并将其发送给鲍勃
routine that a thousand times will
reduce one from Alice and send it to Bob
并发运行，我有另一个循环去循环
and concurrently running I have this
other go routine that in a loop will
从Bob减少一个并将其发送给Alice，注意我这里有这个互斥锁
reduce one from Bob and send it to Alice
and notice that I have this mutex here
每当我操纵这两个不同
and whenever I manipulate these shared
variables between these two different
线程，我总是锁定互斥锁，这
threads
I'm always locking the mutex and this
仅在正确锁定此锁的情况下才会进行更新，因此此代码正确吗
update only happens while this lock is
held right and so is this code correct
或不正确，实际上并没有一个简单的答案
or incorrect there actually isn't really
a straightforward answer to that
问题取决于我的银行的语义是什么样的行为
question it depends on like what are the
semantics of my bank like what behavior
我期望如此，所以我将在这里介绍另一个线程，我将其称为
do I expect so I'm going to introduce
another thread here I'll call this one
审核线程，这是我偶尔要做的
the audit thread and what this is going
to do is every once in a while I'll
检查它，检查我银行中所有帐户的总和，并确保
check it check the sum of all the
accounts in my bank and make sure that
总和与开始时的相同
the sum is the same as what it started
out as
如果我只允许在我的银行内进行转帐，请右键单击
right click if I only allow transfers
within my bank the total amount should
永远不会改变，所以现在给定另一个线程，那么它所做的就是抓住
never change so now given this other
thread so what this does is it grabs the
然后将锁汇总为Alice Plus Bob，并将其与总数进行比较（如果有）
lock then sums up Alice Plus Bob and
compares it to the total and if it
不匹配，则表示尽管我观察到一些违规行为，
doesn't match then it says that though
I've observed some violation that my
总的来说，如果我运行此代码，则不再是应该的，我实际上看到
total is no longer what it should be if
I run this code I actually see that a
这个并发运行的线程的整个时间
whole bunch of times
this concurrently running thread does
确实观察到Alice Plus Bob不等于总和，所以
indeed observe that Alice Plus Bob is
not equal to the overall sum so what
在这里出错了，就像我们在每次访问时都遵循基本规则
went wrong here like we're following our
basic rule of whenever we're accessing
线程之间共享的数据我们抓住了一个锁，这确实是事实，
data that's shared between threads we
grab a lock it is indeed true that no
这些共享变量的更新发生在未完全持有锁的情况下，因此
updates to these shared variables happen
while the lock is not held exactly so
让我重复一遍，让每个人都听到我们在此的意图
let me repeat that for everybody to hear
what we intended here was for this
减少和增加是原子发生的，而不是我们结束的结果
decrement and increment to happen
atomically but instead of what we ended
写的是原子递减然后递增的代码
up writing was code that decrement
atomically and then increments
从原子上讲，因此在此特定代码中实际上就像我们不会赔钱
atomically and so in this particular
code actually like we won't lose money
从长远来看，如果我们让这些线程运行，然后等到它们
in the long term like if we let these
threads run and then wait till they
完成，然后检查总数，它的确会是刚开始时的样子，但是
finish and then check the total it will
indeed be what it started out as but
由于这些完整的代码块不是原子的，因此它们正在运行
while these are running since this
entire block of code is not atomic we
可以暂时观察这些违规行为，因此在更高层次上应该
can temporarily observe these violations
and so at a higher level the way should
考虑锁定不只是锁定可以保护对共享的访问
think about locking is not just like
locks are to protect access to shared
数据，但是锁是为了保护您拥有一些共享数据的不变量
data but locks are meant to protect
invariants you have some shared data
可能会被多个人访问，并且存在一些保留的属性
that multiple people might access and
there's some properties that hold on
像这里这样的共享数据，我是程序员决定我想要的
that shared data like for example here I
is the programmer decided that I want
爱丽丝（Alice）和鲍勃（Bob）的这个属性应该等于某个常数，并且应该
this property that alice + Bob should
equal some constant and that should
总是这样，我希望保留该财产，但事实可能是这样
always be that way I want that property
to hold but then it may be the case that
同时运行的不同线程正在对此数据进行更改，并且
different threads running concurrently
are making changes to this data and
当我递减时可能会像这里一样暂时打破这里的不变式
might temporarily break this invariant
here right like here when I decrement
从Alice那里临时得到的总和Alice Plus Bob改变了，但是
from Alice temporarily the sum Alice
Plus Bob has changed but then this
线程最终会在此处恢复此不变式，因此锁旨在
thread eventually ends up restoring this
invariant here and so locks are meant to
保护并在高水平上变化，您将抓住一把锁，然后您
protect and vary
at a high level you grab a lock then you
做一些可能会暂时打破不变性的工作，但随后您恢复了
do some work that might temporarily
break the invariant but then you restore
释放锁之前的不变式，因此没有人可以观察到这些
the invariant before you release the
lock so nobody can observe these in
进度更新，因此编写此代码的正确方法是实际拥有
progress updates and so the correct way
to write this code is to actually have
少使用锁和解锁，我们有锁，然后我们要做很多工作
less use of lock and unlock
we have lock then we do a bunch of work
然后我们解锁，当您运行此代码时，我们不再看到像这样的打印输出
and then we unlock and when you run this
code we see no more printouts like this
我们从来没有这个审核线程，请注意总数不是
that we never have this audit thread
observe that the total is not what it
应该没事，所以这是思考锁定某种情况的正确方法
should be all right so that's the right
way to think about locking at kind of a
高水平的您可以考虑一下，确保每次
high level you can think about it as
make sure you grab locks when every
像这样访问共享数据是一个规则，但是另一个重要规则是锁
access shared data like that is a rule
but another important rule is locks
保护不变量，因此抢一把锁以某种可能的方式操纵事物
protect invariants so grab a lock
manipulate things in a way that might
打破不变式，但随后将其还原，然后释放锁
break the invariants but restore them
afterwards and then release the lock
您可以考虑的另一种方法是锁可以使代码区域原子化
another way you can think about it is
locks can make regions of code atomic
不只是单个语句或共享变量的单个更新
not just like single statements or
single updates to shared variables any
关于这个伟大的问题，所以我们将要讨论的下一个同步原语
questions about that great so the next
synchronization primitive we're going to
谈论它称为条件变量，这似乎是
talk about it something called condition
variables and this is it seems like
实验室之一引起了我们的困惑
there's been a source of confusion from
lab one where we mentioned condition
变量，但并没有完全解释它们，因此我们将花一些时间
variables but didn't quite explain them
so we're going to take the time to
现在向您解释它们，我们将在一个示例的背景下进行说明
explain them to you now and we're going
to do that in the context of an example
你们应该都熟悉点票，所以请记住在实验2a中
that you should all be familiar with
counting votes so remember in lab 2a you
有这种模式，只要拉夫·皮埃尔（Raph Pierre）成为候选人，
have this pattern where whenever Raph
Pierre becomes a candidate it wants to
发出投票请求，要求所有追随者，最终追随者
send out vote requests all of its
followers and eventually the followers
回到候选人那里，对候选人说“是”或“不”
come back to the candidate and say yes
or no like whether or not the candidate
获得投票权，我们编写此代码的一种方法是让候选人进入
got the vote right and one way we could
write this code is have the candidate in
连环问皮埃尔第一号车第二号为第三号，依此类推，但
serial ask Pierre number one car number
two for number three and so on but
那是不好的权利，因为我们希望候选人同时询问所有同龄人
that's bad right because we want the
candidate ask all the peers in parallel
因此它可以在可能的情况下快速赢得选举，然后还有其他一些
so it can quickly win the election when
possible and then there's some other
那里的复杂性，例如当我们并行询问所有同伴时，我们不想
complexities there like when we ask all
the peers in parallel we don't want to
等一下，让我们在所有人下定决心之前得到所有人的回应
wait so we get a response from all of
them before making up our mind right
因为如果候选人获得像这样的多数票，则无需等待
because if a candidate gets a majority
of votes like it doesn't need to wait
直到收到其他人的回音，所以这段代码有点复杂
till it hears back from everybody else
so this code is kind of complicated in
有些方法，所以这是该投票的残酷版本
some ways and so here here's a kind of
stubbed out version of what that vote
计数代码可能看起来需要一点基础架构
counting code might look like
with a little bit of infrastructure to
使其实际运行，因此这里具有设置计数的平均goroutine
make it actually run and so here have
this mean goroutine that sets count
就像我的赞成票数为零并完成为零
which is like the number of yes votes I
got to zero and finish to zero finished
作为我总共收到的回复数，想法是我想发送
as the number of responses I've gotten
in total and the idea is I want to send
并行发出投票请求，并跟踪我有多少个赞成票以及如何
out vote requests in parallel and keep
track of how many yeses I've got and how
我得到了很多回复，然后一旦我知道我是否赢了
many responses I've gotten in general
and then once I know whether I've won
选举还是我知道我输了选举，那么我可以确定
the election or whether I know that I've
lost the election then I can determine
然后继续前进，就像真正的筏代码一样，您实际上可以执行所需的任何操作
that and move on and like the real raft
code you actually do whatever you need
做完之后，不要升任领导者或降职为跟随者
to do don't step up to a leader or to
step down to a follower after you have
结果，所以在这里看这段代码，我将并行执行
the result from this and so looking at
this code here I'm going to in parallel
旋转说我有十个同伴并行生成十个goroutine
spun say I have ten peers in parallel
spawn ten goroutines
在这里，我在此关闭此链接，我要做的是请求投票，然后如果我
here I pass in this closure here and I'm
gonna do is request a vote and then if I
得到投票，我将计数加一，然后我还将
get the vote I'm going to increment the
count by one and then I'm also going to
将这个完成加一，所以像这样，是的，这是总数
increment this finished by one so like
this is a number of yeses this is total
我得到的答复数量，然后在主执行例程的此处之外进行
number of responses I've gotten and then
outside here in the main go routine what
我正在做的是跟踪这种情况我正在等待这种情况
I'm doing is keeping track of this
condition I'm waiting for this condition
要成为事实，要么我有足够的赞成票赢得了选举，要么
to become true that either I have enough
yes votes that I've won the election or
我已经收到足够多的同龄人的回音，我知道自己迷路了，所以我只是
I've heard back from enough peers and I
know that I've lost and so I'm just
进入循环检查以查看并等待直到计数大于或
going to in a in a loop check to see and
wait until count is greater than or
等于五或等到完成等于十，然后
equal to five or wait until finished is
equal to ten and then after that's the
情况下，我可以确定自己丢失了一个驱动器，那么有人看到了吗
case I can either determine that I've
lost drive one so does anybody see any
鉴于我们刚才讨论的互斥锁，此代码存在问题是
problems with this code given what we
just talked about about mutexes yes
是的，Countin完全没有受到保护
yeah exactly
countin finished aren't protected by
互斥锁，因此我们当然需要在此处修复的一件事是
mutexes so one thing we certainly need
to fix here is that whenever we have
共享变量，我们需要使用新的税收来保护访问权限，因此这不是
shared variables we need to protect
access with new taxes and so that's not
太糟糕了，无法在这里修复我声明了每个人都可以访问的互斥量，然后
too bad to fix here I declare mutex
that's accessible by everybody and then
在执行例行程序时，我将并行启动以请求投票
in the go routines I'm launching in
parallel to request votes I'm going to
这个模式在这里非常重要，我要先请求一个
and this this pattern here is pretty
important I'm going to first request a
在不握锁的情况下进行投票，然后在穿上之后要抓住
vote while I'm not holding the lock and
then after wear that I'm going to grab
锁定，然后更新这些共享变量，然后在外部
the lock and then update these shared
variables and then outside I have the
与以前相同的模式，除了我确保阅读之间可以锁定和解锁
same patterns as before except I make
sure to lock and unlock between reading
这些共享变量，所以在无限循环中，我抓住了锁并检查是否
these shared variables so in an infinite
loop I grab the lock and check to see if
选举的结果已经决定了这一点，如果不是，我就是
the results of the election have been
determined by this point and if not I'm
将继续在这个无限循环中运行，否则我将解锁并执行
going to keep running in this infinite
loop otherwise I'll unlock and then do
我需要在这里以外做些什么，所以如果我运行此示例，那似乎
what I need to do outside of here and so
if I run this example whoops it seems to
工作，这实际上就像是正确的实现，它做对了
work and this is actually like a correct
implementation it does the right thing
但是它有一些问题，所以任何人都可以认识到这个问题
but there's some problems with it so can
anybody recognize any problems with this
实现我会给你一个提示，这段代码并不像它可能的那么好
implementation I'll give you a hint this
code is not as nice as it could be
所以不太会等到正确的时间
so not quite it's going to wait for
exactly the right amount of time the
这里的问题是它正忙于等待它的工作处于非常紧密的循环中
issue here is that it's busy waiting
what it's doing is in a very tight loop
它正在抓锁，检查这种情况解锁抓握此锁
it's grabbing the lock checking this
condition unlocking grabbing this lock
检查此条件解锁，它将消耗一个CPU的100％CPU
checking this condition unlocking and
it's going to burn up 100% CPU on one
核心，因此此代码是正确的，但是就像在较高级别
core while it's doing this so this code
is correct but it's like at a high level
在实验室中，我们不关心CPU效率之类的效率
we don't care about efficiency like CPU
efficiency for the purpose of the labs
但是，如果您使用的是一个内核的100％，则实际上可能会减慢速度
but if you're using a hundred percent of
one core you might actually slow down
程序的其余部分足够多，以至于无法取得进展，所以这就是为什么
the rest of your program enough that it
won't make progress and so that's why
这种模式很糟糕，我们正在消耗100％的CPU等待
this pattern is bad that we're burning
up a hundred percent CPU waiting for
有一定条件成为正确的权利，所以任何人对我们如何有任何想法
some condition to become true right so
does anybody have any ideas for how we
可以解决这个问题，所以这是一个简单的解决方案
could fix this so here's one simple
solution
我将更改一行代码，仅在此处添加50
I will change a single line of code all
I've added here is wait for 50
毫秒，所以这是该程序的正确转换
milliseconds and so this is a correct
transformation of that program and it
似乎可以解决问题，就像我快要烧一百
kind of seems to solve the problem right
like before I was burning up a hundred
现在我每隔50毫秒只唤醒一次CPU百分比
percent CPU now only once every 50
milliseconds I'm going to briefly wake
起来检查这种情况，然后回去睡觉
up check this condition and go back to
sleep
如果它不成立，那么这基本上就像一个可行的解决方案
if it doesn't hold and so this is like
basically a working solution any
问题，所以这种排序有效，但您应该始终注意一件事
questions so this kind of sorta works
but one thing you should always be aware
每当您编写代码时，魔术常数就会变为50毫秒
of whenever you write code is magic
constants why is this 50 milliseconds
为什么不使用其他数字，例如您的任意数字
why not a different number like whenever
you have an arbitrary number in your
编码，这表明您正在做的事情不太正确或不正确
code it's a sign that you're doing
something that's not quite right or not
相当干净，所以事实证明存在并发
quite as clean as it could be and so it
turns out that there's a concurrency
旨在解决这个问题的原语，我正在运行一些线程
primitive designed to solve exactly this
problem of I have some threads running
同时更新一些共享数据，然后我有另一个
concurrently that are making updates to
some shared data and then I have another
正在等待某些属性的线程，该共享数据上的某些条件
thread that's waiting for some property
some condition on that shared data to
变为真，直到该条件变为真，线程才进入
become true and until that condition
becomes true the thread is just going to
等等，有一个专门用来解决这个问题的工具，那是一个工具
wait there's a tool designed exactly to
solve this problem and that's a tool
称为条件变量，而您使用条件变量的方式是
called a condition variable and the way
you use a condition variable is the
模式基本上看起来像这样，所以我们已经锁定了较早的条件
pattern basically looks like this so we
have our lock from earlier condition
变量与锁相关联，所以我们有一些共享数据，还有一些锁
variables are associated with locks so
we have some shared data some a lock
保护共享数据，然后我们有这个条件变量
that protects that shared data and then
we have this condition variable that is
在初始化时给定了一个指向锁的指针，我们将使用它
given a pointer to the lock when it's
initialized and we're going to use this
条件变量，用于在特定条件下进行协调
condition variable for kind of
coordinating when a certain condition
共享数据上的一些属性变为真时，以及我们修改的方式
some property on that shared data when
that becomes true and the way we modify
我们的代码就像我们有两个地方一样，我们正在对该数据进行更改，
our code is like we have two places one
we're making changes to that data which
可能使条件变为真，然后我们在另一个地方
might make the condition become true and
then we have another place where we're
等待该条件变为真，并且通常的模式是
waiting for that condition to become
true and the general pattern is whenever
我们做一些改变数据的事情，我们称之为行为广播，我们这样做
we do something that changes the data we
call a conduct broadcast and we do this
按住锁，然后在另一边等待
while holding the lock and then on the
other side where we're waiting for some
在共享数据变为真的条件下，我们称之为点等待，等等
condition on that share data to become
true we call con dot wait and so what
这确实就像让我们考虑一下平均线程中会发生什么
this does is like let's think about what
happens in the mean thread for a moment
主线程抓住锁，如果它是假的，则检查此条件
the main thread grabs the lock it checks
this condition suppose it's false it
调用con dot等一下，这会是原子的，您可以想到它
calls con dot wait what this will do is
it will atomically you can think of it
因为它将释放锁，以便让其他人获得进步，并且它将
as it'll release the lock in order to
let other people make progress and it'll
添加它的线程，就像将其添加到正在等待的人的类似列表中
add its thread like it'll add itself to
a like list of people who are waiting on
此条件变量，然后并发这些线程之一可能
this condition variable then
concurrently one of these threads might
可以在投票后获得锁，然后进行操纵
be able to acquire the lock after it's
gotten a vote and then it manipulates
这些变量，然后调用进行广播，这是做什么的
these variables and then it calls
conduct broadcast what that does is it
唤醒等待条件变量的人，因此一旦
wakes up whoever's waiting on the
condition variable and so once this
线程解锁互斥锁，这是我们想要的，因为它从等待返回
thread unlocks the mutex this one what
do we want as it's returning from wait
我们将重新获取互斥锁，然后返回到此for循环的顶部
we'll reacquire the mutex and then
return to the top of this for loop which
正在检查这种情况，因此无论谁在等待，此广播都会唤醒
is checking this condition so this
broadcast wakes up whoever's waiting at
这样的等待，这样可以避免一定时间点套
this wait and so this avoids having to
have that time dot sleeve for some
像这个线程那样等待某个条件的任意时间
arbitrary amount of time like this
thread that's waiting for some condition
只有在某些变化可能使之成为现实的时候醒悟
to become true only gets woken up when
something changes that might make that
条件变为真，就像如果您考虑这些线程，
condition become true right like if you
think about these threads if they're
非常慢，他们很长一段时间都不会叫出conned out广播
very slow and they don't call conned out
broadcast for a long time this one will
只是在等待，这不会像定期唤醒并检查一些
just be waiting it won't be like
periodically waking up and checking some
不能改变的状况，因为没有其他人操纵他们的
condition that can't have changed
because nobody else manipulated their
共享数据，所以对此模式有任何疑问吗
shared data so any questions about this
pattern yeah
所以这是一个很好的问题，我认为您指的是所谓的
so that's a great question I think
you're referring to something called the
丢失的唤醒问题，这是操作系统中的主题，我们不会谈论
lost wake up problem and this is a topic
in operating systems and we won't talk
关于它的细节，现在可以在演讲后随意问我，但是很高
about it in detail now there feel free
to ask me after lecture but at a high
级别，您可以避免在
level you can avoid funny race
conditions that might happen between
等待并按照我在此处显示的特定模式进行广播，然后
wait and broadcast by following the
particular pattern I'm showing here and
稍后，我将向您展示此模式的抽象版本
I'll show you an abstracted version of
this pattern in a moment basically the
模式是针对可能进行更改以改变结果的那一面
pattern is for the side that might make
changes that will change the outcome of
您总是锁定条件测试然后处理数据然后调用广播
the condition test you always lock then
manipulate the data then call broadcast
然后呼叫解锁，因此必须在按住时呼叫广播
and call unlock afterwards so the
broadcast must be called while holding
同样，当您检查状况时，您会抓住锁，然后
the lock similarly when you're checking
the condition you grab the lock then
您总是先循环检查条件，然后再检查内部条件
you're always checking the condition in
a loop and then inside so when that
条件为假，请致电Condit等待，仅在您持有时调用
condition is false you call Condit wait
this is only called while you're holding
锁，并且原子地释放锁和诸如put之类的时间表
the lock and it atomically releases the
lock and kind of schedule like puts
本身在等待线程的列表中，然后等待返回，如我们所愿
itself in a list of waiting threads and
then as waits returning so as we like
从此等待调用返回，然后返回到此for循环的顶部，它将
return from this wait call and then go
back to the top of this for loop it will
重新获取锁，以便仅在持有锁的同时进行此检查，并且
reacquire the lock so this check will
only happen while holding the lock and
那么在此之外，我们仍然在这里拥有锁，我们在
then so outside of this we still have
the lock here and we unlock after we're
完成了我们在这里需要做的所有事情，这种模式看起来像
done doing whatever we need to do here
at a high level this pattern looks like
这样我们就有一个线程或一些线程在做一些
this so we have one thread or some
number of threads doing something that
可能会影响病情，因此他们将要抢一把锁
might affect the condition so they're
going to grab a lock do the thing call
广播，然后调用解锁，另一方面，我们有一些线程
broadcast then call unlock and on the
other side we have some thread that's
等待某种条件成真，那里的模式看起来像我们
waiting for some condition to become
true the pattern there it looks like we
在条件为假的情况下在一段时间的循环中抓住锁，然后我们等待，如此
grab the lock then in a while loop while
the condition is false we wait and so
那么我们知道当我们经过这个while循环时，条件为真，
then we know that when we get past this
while loop now the condition is true and
我们拿着锁，我们可以做任何我们需要做的事，然后
we're holding the lock and we can do
whatever we need to do here and then
最后我们称之为解锁，以便我们讨论所有可能出错的地方
finally we call unlock so we can talk
about all the things that might go wrong
如果您有兴趣，但如果违反了这些规则之一，例如课后
if you violate one of these rules like
after lecture if you're interested but
如果您遵循这种模式，那么就不需要处理
at a high level if you follow this
pattern then you won't need to deal with
这些问题，所以对此有任何疑问
those issues so any questions about that
是的
yeah
所以这是一个很大的问题，何时使用广播以及何时使用
so that's a great question
when do you use broadcast versus when do
使用信号，以便交谈有三种方法，一种是等待
等待端，然后在另一端，您可以使用信号或广播，
waiting side and then on the other side
you can use signal or broadcast and the
这些的语义是信号等待，就像一个线程一样唤醒一个侍者
semantics of those are signal wait wakes
up exactly one waiter like one thread
可能正在等待，而广播唤醒了所有人
that may be waiting
whereas broadcast wakes up everybody
谁在等待，他们都会伸出援手，就像他们都将尽力争取法律。
who's waiting and they'll all reach out
like they'll all try to grab the law can
重新检查条件，只有其中一个会继续，因为只有一个
recheck the condition and only one of
them will proceed because only one a
他会把门锁小一点直到它超过这一点
little he'll door lock until it gets
past this point I think for the purpose
如果遵循此模式，则此类的所有人始终使用广播，从不使用信号
of this class always use broadcast never
use signal if you follow this pattern
就像不使用信号并始终使用广播一样，您的代码也可以正常工作
and just like don't use signal and
always use broadcast your code will work
我认为您可以将信号视为提高效率的工具，我们
对此，我并不真正在意实验室中的CPU效率水平
don't really care about that level of
CPU efficiency in the labs for this
类
class
好的，还有更多问题，所以我们将在围棋方面讨论最后一个主题
any more questions ok so the final topic
we're going to cover in terms of go
并发原语是通道，所以两个高级通道就像一个队列
concurrency primitives is channels so
two high level channels are like a queue
像同步原语，但它们的行为不像
like synchronization primitive but they
don't behave quite like cues in the
直觉的感觉，就像我认为有人想到渠道一样
intuitive sense like I think some people
think of channels is like there's this
数据结构，我们可以坚持下去，最终将有人
data structure we can sticks that stick
things in and eventually someone will
撤消这些东西，但实际上渠道没有排队能力
pull those things out but in fact
channels have no queuing capacity they
没有内部存储，基本上，如果需要，通道是同步的
have no internal storage basically
channels are synchronous if you have to
如果有人尝试去在频道上发送和接收的例程
go routines that are going to send and
receive on a channel if someone tries to
在没有人接收该线程的情况下在通道上发送消息，直到阻塞
send on the channel while nobody's
receiving that thread will block until
有人准备好接收，并在那时同步交换
somebody's ready to receive and at that
point synchronously it will exchange
那个数据传给接收者，如果另一个方向相同
that data over to the receiver and the
same is true the other direction if
有人试图从某个频道接收，而没有人发送，该接收将会
someone tries to receive from a channel
while nobody's sending that receive will
阻塞，直到有另一个goroutine要在频道上发送，并且
block until there's another goroutine
that's about to send on the channel and
发送将同步发生，所以这是一个小演示程序，
that send will happen synchronously so
here's a little demo program that
在这里演示这一点，我有一个我声明的频道，然后生成一个go
demonstrates this here I have a I
declare channel and then I spawn a go
例程，等待一秒钟，然后发送，然后从通道接收
routine that waits for a second and then
sent and then receives from a channel
然后在我的主要女孩子例程中，我跟踪时间，然后发送
and then in my main girl routine I keep
track of the time then I send on the
通道，所以我只是将一些虚拟数据放入通道中，然后我将
channel so I just put some dummy data
into the channel and then I'm going to
打印发送多长时间
print out how long the send took
如果您将渠道视为具有内部存储容量的线索，则可能
and if you think of channels as cues
with internal storage capacity you might
认为这件事完成得非常快，但这不是渠道的运作方式
think of this thing as completing very
fast but that's not how channels work
该发送将被阻止，直到发生接收和发生
this send is going to block until this
receive happens and this one happened
直到这一秒过去了，所以从这里到这里
till this one second is the elapsed and
so from here to here
实际上，我们在主流程中被阻塞了一秒钟
we're actually blocked in the main goo
routine for one whole second alright so
不要将通道视为队列，而是将其视为同步
don't think of channels as queues think
of them as this synchronous like the
同步通讯机制
synchronous communication mechanism
另一个使这一点很明显的例子是在这里，我们有一个goroutine
another example that'll make this really
obvious is here we have a goroutine that
创建一个频道，然后在该频道上发送并尝试从中接收
creates a channel then sends on the
channel and tries receiving from it
当我尝试运行此程序时，没人知道会发生什么
doesn't anybody know what'll happen when
I try running this
我认为文件名可能会把它丢掉
I think the file name might give it away
是的，发送将一直阻塞，直到有人准备接收，但是
yeah exactly the send is going to block
till somebody's ready to receive but
没有接收器，如果您所有的人都去实际检测到这种情况
there is no receiver and go actually
detects this condition if all your
线程正在将其休眠以发送文本，这是一个死锁条件，实际上
threads are sleeping it to text this is
a deadlock condition and it'll actually
崩溃，但如果有其他线程，您可能会有更多细微的错误
crash but you can have more subtle bugs
where if you have some other thread like
如果我生成了您知道for循环的go例程，就不要做某事
off doing something if I spawn this go
routine that you know for loop does
什么都没有，我尝试再次运行该程序，现在它进入了死锁检测器
nothing and I try running this program
again now it goes deadlock detector
不会注意到所有线程都没有使用任何东西，就像有一个
won't notice that all threads are not
doing any use will work like there's one
线程正在运行，只是这从未收到，我们可以通过查看
thread running it's just this is never
receiving and we can tell by looking at
这个程序，它永远不会终止，但在这里看起来就像挂着一样
this program that it'll never terminate
but here it just looks like it hangs so
如果您不小心使用频道，则可以在这些地方找到这些细微的错误
if you're not careful with channels you
can get these subtle bugs where you have
结果是X的两倍，是的，完全没有任何人在发送数据
double X as a result yeah yeah exactly
there's no data nobody's sending on this
频道，所以这将在这里阻塞，永远不会到达这条线
channel so this is gonna block here it's
never gonna get to this line
是的，因此您所指出的渠道实际上不能仅在
yeah so channels as you pointed out
can't really be used just within a
单个goroutine并没有任何意义，因为为了发送或发送
single goroutine it doesn't really make
sense because in order to send or in
为了接收，必须有另一个go例程在执行相反的操作
order to receive there has to be another
go routine doing the opposite action at
同时，所以如果没有的话，你将永远受阻，然后
the same time so if there isn't you're
just gonna block forever and then that
ch，但线程将不再做任何有用的工作，是的，等待接收
chant but thread will no longer do any
useful work yeah sans wait for receives
收到等待迹象，并且一旦同时发生
receives wait for signs and it happens
synchronously once there's both the
发送者和接收者表示我到目前为止所谈论的内容是无缓冲的
sender and receiver present what I
talked about so far is unbuffered
我本来要避免谈论缓冲通道，因为那里
channels I was going to avoid talking
about buffered channels because there
很少有问题对于解决如此缓冲的问题实际上有用
are very few problems that they're
actually useful for solving so buffered
频道可以容纳一定的容量，然后您就可以想到它了，因为它只是切换
channels can take in a capacity and then
you can think of it as it's just switch
这就是这个程序的容量为1的缓冲通道
this to so here's a buffered channel
with a capacity of one this program does
终止是因为缓冲的通道就像它们有一些内部存储
terminate because buffered channels are
like they have some internal storage
空间，直到该空间填满为止，发送不会阻塞，因为它们可以
space and until that space fills up
sends are non blocking because they can
只需将数据放入内部存储空间即可，但一旦通道
just put that data in the internal
storage space but once the channel does
填满，那么它的行为就像修女缓冲通道
fill up then it does behave like a nun
buffer channel in the sense that further
发送将一直阻塞，直到在通道中有接收空间为止，但是我认为
sends will block until there's a receive
to make space in the channel but I think
在较高的层次上，我们应该避免缓冲通道，因为它们基本上不会
at a high level we should avoid buffered
channels because they basically don't
解决任何问题，另一条路径和其他应该考虑的事情是
solve any problems and another path and
other things should be thinking about is
每当你在这里编造任意数字来使你的
whenever you to make up arbitrary
numbers like this one here to make your
代码工作，您可能做错了是的
code work you're probably doing
something wrong yeah
所以我认为这是一个关于术语的问题
so I think this is a question about
terminology like what exactly does
死锁意味着该死锁是一个死锁，像是的，这算作一个死锁
deadlock mean into this count as a
deadlock like yes this counts as a
死锁就像没有有用的进展将在这里这样，这些线程是
deadlock like no useful progress will be
made here like this these threads are
永远困扰着其他任何问题，那么我们的频道
just stuck forever
any other questions so what our channel
我认为渠道对一小部分事情很有用，例如
is useful for I think channels are
useful for a small set of things like
例如，我认为对于生产者消费者队列，诸如此类的情况
for example I think for producer
consumer queues sort of situations like
在这里，我有一个制作频道的程序，它产生了一堆
here I have a program that makes a
channel and this spawns a bunch of
goroutine会做一些工作，例如说他们正在竞争
goroutines that are going to be doing
some work like say they're competing
产生一些数据的结果，我有很多这样的例程
some result in producing some data and I
have a bunch of these go routines
并行运行，我想收集所有传入的数据，
running in parallel and I want to
collect all that data as it comes in and
用它做一些事情，所以这就像等待一样
do something with it
so this do work thing just like waits
并产生一个随机数，在主goroutine中，我将
for a bit and produces a random number
and in the main goroutine I'm going to
不断在此频道上接收并打印出来，因为这是对
continuously receive on this channel and
print it out like this is a great use of
渠道渠道的另一个很好的用途是实现类似于
channels another good use of channels is
to achieve something similar to what
等待组这样做而不是使用等待组，因为我想产生一堆
wait groups do so rather than use a wait
group suppose I want to spawn a bunch of
线程，直到他们都完成某件事为止，一种方法是
threads and wait till they're all done
doing something one way to do that is to
创建一个通道，然后生成一堆线程，然后知道有多少
create a channel and then I spawn a
bunch of threads and know how many
我生成的线程，因此将在此处创建五个goroutine
threads I've spawned so five goroutines
created here they're going to do
内容，然后在完成后在此频道上发送，然后在主要
something and then send on this channel
when they're done and then in the main
去例行程序，我可以从那个频道收到相同的次数，
go routine I can just receive from that
channel the same number of times and
这与等待组具有相同的效果
this has the same effect as a wait group
这样的问题到底是什么问题
so question so what exactly is the
question
[音乐]
[Music]
所以这里的问题是，您是否可以使用容量为5的缓冲通道
so the question is here could you use a
buffered channel with a capacity of five
因为您正在等待五个收件我认为在这种情况下
because you're waiting for five receives
I think in this particular case yes that
会产生相同的效果，但我认为没有真正理由
would have the equivalent effect but I
think there's not really a reason to do
我认为在您的代码中
that
and I think at a high level in your code
您应该避免使用缓冲通道，甚至避免使用通道，除非您
you should avoid buffer channels and
also maybe even channels unless you
认真思考自己在做什么，所以我认为一个体重组是什么
think very hard about what you're doing
yeah so what is a weight group I think
我们在之前的讲座中谈到了这一点，今天我简短地谈到了
we covered this in a previous lecture
and I talked about it very briefly today
但是我有一个重量组的例子，所以重量组是一个
but I do have an example of weight
groups so a weight group is a yet
go在sync包中提供的另一个同步原语和
another synchronization primitive
provided by go in the sync package and
就像他的名字所宣传的那样，它可以让您等待某个
it kind of does what his name advertises
like it lets you wait for a certain
工作方式的线程数是您调用权重组点添加
number of threads to be done the way it
works is you call weight group dot add
这基本上会增加一些内部计数器，然后当您调用
and that basically increments some
internal counter and then when you call
权重组点权重，它等待完成的次数已与广告调用了多次
weight group dot weight it waits till
done has been called as many times as ad
被调用，因此该代码与我刚刚向您展示的代码基本相同
was called so this code is basically the
same as the code I just showed you that
使用了一个频道，除了使用权重组，它们具有完全相同的
was using a channel except this is using
weight group they have the exact same
效果你可以使用一个
effect you can use either one yeah
所以这里的问题是关于比赛条件，我想如果
so the question here is about race
conditions I think like what happens if
此广告在发生这种重量或其他事情之前发生的速度不够快
this ad doesn't happen fast enough
before this weight happens or something
像这样好，所以请注意这里的模式是称重组
like that well so here notice that the
pattern here is we call weight group
go例程之外的数据，并且在生成该go例程之前被调用
data outside of this go routine and it's
called before spawning this go routine
所以首先发生，然后发生，所以我们永远不会遇到这种情况
so this happens first this happens next
and so we'll never have the situation
我们做完了这个广告，就发生在这个特定的例行程序之后
we're done happens after this ad happens
for this particular routine how's this
由编译器实现，我现在不再讨论
implemented by the compiler and I will
not talk about that now but talk to me
下课后或上班时间，但我认为像您这样的目的班
after class or in office hours but I
think for the purposes class like you
需要了解这些事情的API而不是正确的实现等等
need to know the API for these things
not the implementation all right and so
我认为基本上这是我正在进行的所有并发原语，所以最后
I think that's basically all I have on
go concurrency primitives so one final
思想是在诸如此类的渠道上对像我这样的特定事物有好处
thought is on channels like channels are
good for a specific set of things like I
只是向您显示了生产者消费者队列或喜欢实施某些东西
just showed you the producer consumer
queue or like implementing something
像重量组，但我认为当您尝试与他们做更奇特的事情时
like weight groups but I think when you
try to do fancier things with them like
如果您想说像踢另一个可能正在或可能不等待的跑步程序
if you want to say like kick another go
routine that may or may not be waiting
对于您来说就像被唤醒一样，这与频道有关
for you to be like woken up that's a
kind of tricky thing to do with channels
还有很多其他方法可以让他们跟自己开枪
there's also a bunch of other ways to
shoot yourself in the foot with them I'm
避免向您展示带有频道的错误代码示例，因为
going to avoid showing you examples of
bad code with channels just because it's
看不见有用，但我个人大部分时间避免使用渠道，并且
not useful to see but I personally avoid
using channels for the most part and
只需使用共享内存和互斥锁以及条件变量，然后设置和
just use shared memory and mutexes and
condition variables and set and I
亲自找到那些更容易推理的东西，所以可以随时使用
personally find those much easier to
reason about so feel free to use
有意义的渠道，但如果有什么事情看起来特别尴尬，
channels for when they make sense but if
anything looks especially awkward to do
使用诸如互斥和条件变量之类的通道，它们可能是
with channels like just use mutexes and
condition variables and they're probably
是更好的工具
a better tool yeah
所以问题在于这种生产者-消费者模式之间的差异
so the question is with the difference
between this producer-consumer pattern
在线程安全的FIFO中，我认为它们和您一样
here in a thread-safe FIFO I think
they're kind of equivalent like you
可以使用线程安全的FIFO做到这一点，基本上这就是
could do this with the thread-safe FIFO
and it like that is basically what a
如果您正在Indy中排队，那么缓冲通道就差不多
like buffered channel is roughly if
you're in queueing things in Indy
排队之类的事情，如果您希望此行结束并让该线程执行
queueing things like if you want this
line to finish and have this thread go
当数据排在队列而不是这个女孩那里时做其他事情
do something else while that data sits
there in a queue rather than this girl
例程等待发送它，那么缓冲的通道可能有意义，但是我
routine waiting to send it then a
buffered channel might make sense but I
认为至少在生活中不会有这样的模式，所以
think at least in the lives you will not
have a pattern like that all right so
下一步Fabian会谈论更快速相关的内容，您需要这个吗
next Fabian's going to talk about more
rapidly related stuff do you need this
好吧，你们都能听到我的声音吗，是的，所以基本上
all right can you all hear me is this
working yeah all right so yeah basically
我将向您展示我们通常在人们的木筏中看到的两个错误
I'm going to show you two bugs that we
commonly see in people's raft
实现中有很多很常见的错误，但我只是
implementations there's a lot of bugs
that are pretty common but I'm just
将重点放在其中的两个上，因此在第一个示例中，我们有点开始
going to focus on two of them so in this
first example we sort of have a start of
筏式实现，就像您可能会看到的
a raft implementation for that's sort of
like what you might see for to a just
一个人的开始，所以在我们的木筏状态下，我们主要
the beginnings of one
so in our raft state we have primarily
筏墩的当前状态，是跟随者候选者还是领导者，以及
the current status of the raft pier
either follower candidate or leader and
我们有这两个状态变量来跟踪当前术语
we have these two state variables that
were keeping track of the current term
以及我们在当前任期内投票支持的人，所以我希望我们重点关注
and who we voted for in the current term
so I'm I want us to focus though on
这两个功能会尝试选举和呼叫请求投票，因此在我们看来
these two functions attempt election and
call request vote so in a temptin we're
只是将我们的状态设置为候选项，以增加我们当前的选票
just going to set our state to candidate
increment our current term vote for
自己，然后开始向所有筏友发送请求投票
ourselves and then start sending out
request votes to all of our raft peers
因此，这类似于Anish展示了我们所处的某些模式
and so this is similar to some of the
patterns that Anish showed where we're
将遍历我们的同伴，然后分别进行每个例程
going to loop through our peers and then
for each one in a go routines separately
调用此呼叫请求投票功能，以实际向该对象发送RPC
call this call request vote function in
order to actually send an RPC to that
同行很好，所以在通话请求投票中
peer
alright so in call request vote we're
将为我们的请求Ville RPC调用获取锁准备参数
going to acquire the lock prepare
arguments for our request Ville RPC call
通过将其设置为当前术语，然后实际执行RPC
based on by setting it to the current
term and then actually perform the RPC
打电话到这里，最后根据回应，我们会回覆这个
call over here and finally based on the
response we will reply back to this this
尝试选举功能和最终尝试选举功能
attempt election function and the
attempt election function eventually
应该汇总一下选票，看看它是否获得多数票，并且可以
should tally up the votes to see if it
got a majority of the votes and can
成为领导者，那么当我们运行此代码时会发生什么，因此理论上我们会
become leader so what happens when we
run this code so in theory what we might
预计会发生四点，所以将会有一些代码
expect to happen is four so there's
going to be some code that's going to
生成一些图形矛，然后尝试尝试对它们进行选举，
spawn a few graph spears and actually
try to attempt elections on them and
应该发生的是，我们只是开始从其他同行那里收集选票，
what should happen are we just start
collecting votes from other peers and
那么我们实际上并不会理清他们
then we're not actually going to tally
them up
但希望没有奇怪的地方出问题，但实际上会发生什么
but hopefully nothing weird goes wrong
but actually something is going to go
错误在这里，我们实际上激活了死锁检测器，并以某种方式我们
wrong here and we actually activated
goes deadlock detector and somehow we
陷入僵局，让我们看看现在发生了什么，让我们专注于发生了什么
ran into a deadlock so let's see what
happened for now let's focus on what's
服务器为零，因此服务器为零，表示开始尝试
going on with the server zero so server
zero it says it starts attempting an
刚开始尝试选举功能的第一学期的选举
election at term one that's just
starting the attempt election function
它将获取锁集，其中一些集用于执行
it will acquire the lock set some of the
set some stuff up for performing the
选择然后解锁，然后它将发出请求投票RPC-服务器
election and then unlock then it's going
to send out a request vote RPC - server
-它完成了对请求RPC的处理，因此我们只是
- it finishes processing that request
vote RPC over here so we're just
在我们实际发出RPC之前和之后进行打印，然后再进行打印
printing right before and after we
actually send out the RPC and then it
发送一个请求投票RPC-服务器一，但是在那之后我们再也没有
sends out a request vote RPC - server
one but after that it never we never
实际上看到它完成了发送请求投票RPC的操作，因此它实际上被卡住了
actually see it finish sending the
request vote RPC so it's actually stuck
在此函数调用中，现在等待服务器1的RPC响应
in this function call waiting for the
RPC response from server 1 all right now
让我们看看每个人在做什么，这几乎是同一件事
let's look at what's everyone's doing so
it's it's pretty much the same thing it
发送请求投票，我收到一台服务器，该服务器成功完成
sends a request vote I received a server
to that that succeeds it finishes
处理该请求投票来自服务器2的响应，然后发送
processing that request vote the
response from server 2 then it sends
RPC为零，现在实际发生的是0＆1，正在等待
this RPC to zero and now what's actually
happening is 0 & 1 are sort of waiting
对于彼此的RPC响应，他们都发出了RPC调用，但没有
for the RPC responses from each other
they both sent out an RPC call but not
尚未得到回应，这实际上是我们的原因
yet got the response yet and that's
actually sort of the cause of our
死锁，所以我们死锁的真正原因是因为我们
deadlock so really what's the reason
that we're dead locking is because we're
通过核心请求投票中的RPC调用来保持此锁
holding this lock through our RPC calls
over here in the core requests vote
函数，我们获取与筏同伴关联的互斥体，并且仅在
function we acquire our mutex associated
with our raft peer and we only unlock at
该函数的结尾，因此在整个函数中，我们将
the end of this function so throughout
this entire function we're holding the
锁定，包括当我们尝试与我们的同伴联系以进行投票时以及随后的时间
lock including when we try to contact
our peer to get the vote and later when
我们处理此请求投票RPC，实际上我们只会在
we handle this request vote RPC we
actually only see it at the beginning of
此函数在处理程序中，我们也在尝试获取锁，但我们从未
this function in the handler we're also
trying to acquire the lock but we never
实际上成功地获得了锁，因此只需多一点
actually succeed in acquiring the lock
so just to make this a little bit more
清除操作顺序
clear the the sort of order of
operations
正在发生在呼叫请求表决服务器零首先要获取
is happening is in call request vote
server zero is first going to acquire
锁定，然后将RPC调用发送到服务器一，然后同时
the lock and send an RPC call to server
one and then simultaneously and
单独的服务器将要执行相同的操作，它将进入其呼叫
separately server one is going to do the
same thing it's going to enter its call
请求投票功能获取锁并将此RPC调用发送到服务器零
request vote function acquire the lock
and send this RPC call to server zero
现在在他们试图获取的服务器零处理程序和服务器一个处理程序中
now in server zeros handler and server
ones handler they're trying to acquire
锁，但是他们不能，因为他们已经在获取锁了，
the lock but they can't because they
already are acquiring the lock and
试图互相发送RPC调用，这实际上是
trying to send the RPC call to each
other and that that's actually what's
导致出现僵局的情况，因此要解决此问题，基本上我们希望您不要
leading to the deadlock situation so to
solve this basically we want you to not
通过RPC调用来保持锁定，这实际上是解决此问题的方法
hold locks through RPC calls and that's
the solution to this problem in fact we
根本不需要这里的锁，而是在需要时尝试读取当前术语
don't need the lock here at all instead
of trying to read the current term when
我们输入此呼叫请求表决功能，可以在此处将其作为参数传递
we enter this call request vote function
we can pass this as an argument here
保留我们在这次尝试选举中较早获得锁的期限
save the term when we had acquired the
lock earlier in this attempt election
并将其作为变量传递给调用请求投票，因此实际上
and just passed this as a as a variable
to call request vote so that actually
消除了在呼叫请求投票中完全获取锁定的需要
removes the need to acquire the lock at
all in call request vote alternatively
我们可以在准备参数时锁定，然后在解锁之前
we could lock while we're preparing the
arguments and then unlock before
实际执行呼叫，然后如果我们需要处理回复，我们可以
actually performing the call and then if
we need to to process the reply we could
之后再次锁定，因此只需确保在解锁之前将其解锁
lock again afterwards so it's just make
sure to unlock before making it
显然会打电话，然后如果您需要的话，您可以再次获取锁，所以现在如果
obviously call and then if you need to
you can acquire the lock again so now if
然后我保存了它，因此它仍在激活死锁检测器，但是
I save this then so it's still
activating the deadlock detector but
那实际上只是因为我们最后什么也没做，但是现在
that's actually just because we're not
doing anything at the end but now it's
实际工作中，我们已完成对请求的发送
actually working
we finished sending the request votes on
双方，我们要完成的所有操作都完成了
both sides and all the operations that
we wanted to complete are complete all
对这个例子有任何疑问
right any questions about this example
是的，不是这样的，所以您在准备时可能需要使用锁
yeah so not it's sort of so you might
need to use locks when you are preparing
参数或处理响应，但是是的，您不应该锁定
the arguments or processing the response
but yeah you shouldn't hold a lock
在等待其他对等方响应时通过RPC调用
through the RPC call while you're
waiting for the other peer to respond
实际上，除了死锁之外，还有另一个原因
and there's actually another reason to
that in addition to deadlock the other
问题是，在某些测试中，我们将有些不可靠
problem is that in some tests we're
going to sort of have this unreliable
网络可能会使您的某些RPC消息延迟约50
network that could delay some of your
RPC messages potentially by like 50
毫秒，在这种情况下，如果您通过RPC调用持有该锁，则
milliseconds and in that case if you
hold the lock through an RPC call then
在这50毫秒内尝试执行的任何其他操作都不会
any other operation that you try to do
during that 50 milliseconds won't be
能够完成直到收到RPC响应，这是另一个问题
able to complete until that RPC response
is received so that that's another issue
如果您持有多头可能会碰到，所以两者都会使事情变得更多
that you might run into if you hold the
long so it's both to make things more
高效并避免这些潜在的僵局情况
efficient and to avoid these potential
deadlock situations
好的，再举一个例子，那就是再次使用类似的草稿
all right so just one more example this
is again using a similar draft
实施，因此在筏状态下，我们将继续跟踪
implementation so again in our raft
state we're going to be keeping track of
是否更充分的候选人领导，然后这两个状态变量
whether a fuller candidate leader and
then also these two state variables in
这个例子我想让你专注于这个尝试选举功能，所以现在我们已经
this example I want you to focus on this
attempt election function so now we've
首先实现了我刚刚向您展示的将术语存储在此处的更改，
first implemented the change that I just
showed you to store the term here and
将其作为变量传递给我们的函数，该函数收集请求票，但
pass it as a variable to our function
that collects the request votes but
此外，我们还实现了一些功能以汇总选票，因此
additionally we've implemented some
functionality to add up the votes so
我们要做的是创建一个局部变量来计算票数
what we'll do is we'll create a local
variable to count the votes and whenever
如果没有投票，我们将投票
we get a vote if the vote was not
granted
我们将立即从处理船的执行例行程序返回
we'll return immediately from this go
routine where we're processing the boat
否则，我们将在将此共享本地变量编辑为
otherwise we'll acquire the lock before
editing this shared local variable to
算一票，然后如果我们没有获得多数票，
count up the votes and then if we did
not get a majority of the votes will
立即返回，否则我们将使自己成为领导者，例如
return immediately otherwise we'll make
ourselves the leader so as with the
另一个例子，我的意思是最初，如果你看着这个，如果我看着这个，
other example I mean initially if you
look at this if I look at this like it
看起来很合理，但让我们看看是否有任何问题可以解决，所以这
seems reasonable but let's see if
anything can go wrong all right so this
是一次运行的日志输出，您可能会注意到的一件事是，我们已经
is the log output from one run and one
thing you might notice is that we've
实际上在同一任期内选举了两名领导人，因此服务器为零
actually elected two leaders on the same
term so server zero
它被选为第二学期的领导者，而服务器一也做得很好
it was elected made itself a leader on
term two and server one did as well it's
可以按不同的条件选举一位领导人，但是在这里
okay to have a leader elected on
different terms but here where we have
一个人认为永远都不会发生，所以这是怎么做到的
one on the same term that that should
never happen alright so how did this
实际上出现了，所以让我们从顶部开始，从服务器零开始
actually come up so let's start from the
top so at the beginning server zero
实际上在第一学期就进行了一次大选而不是第二届大选
actually attempted an election at term
one not turn two and it got its votes
来自其他两个同行，但出于任何原因也许是因为
from both of the other peers but for
whatever reason perhaps because those
那些同行的回复消息被延迟了，实际上并没有处理
reply messages from those peers were
delayed it didn't actually process its
处理这些选票，直到稍后和之间，例如
process those votes until later and in
between receiving it like in between
尝试选举并完成选举服务器的工作也决定
attempting the election and finishing
the election server one also decided to
尝试选举，也许是因为服务器零延迟了所以
attempt an election perhaps because
because of server zero was delayed so
很多服务器可能实际上遇到了选举超时
much server one might
actually ran into the election timeout
然后开始自己的选举，并在第二学期开始选举，因为它不能
and then started its own election and it
started it on term 2 because it couldn't
之所以被称为1，是因为它已经在第1项中对服务器0进行了投票
have been termed 1 because it already
voted for server 0 on on term 1 over
在这里好，然后服务器1发送自己的
here
okay so then server 1 sends out its own
请求在第2学期投票2个服务器2和0，现在我们看到该服务器2个投票
request votes 2 servers 2 and 0 at term
2 and now we see that server two votes
对于服务器1来说很好，但是服务器0也对服务器1投票，这实际上是
for server 1 that's fine but server 0
also votes for server 1 this is actually
也很好，因为服务器一正在要求服务器0投票以获得更高的期限，并且
also fine because server one is asking
server 0 for a vote on a higher term and
所以服务器0应该做的是，如果您从规格中记住它应该设置其
so what server 0 should do is if you
remember from the spec it should set its
术语2中的RPC消息请求中该术语的当前术语
current term to that term in the request
for RPC message to term 2 and also
最后将自己恢复为关注者而不是候选人，所以真正的
revert itself to a follower instead of a
candidate alright finally so the real
问题是在这行服务器0，虽然它确实足够
problem is that on this line where
server 0 although it really got enough
在第1届会议上投票，使自己成为第一个任期的领导者-所以一个
votes on term 1 it made itself a leader
on term - so the reason so one
解释为什么发生这种情况的原因是，在我们设置
explanation for why this is happening is
because in between where we set up the
选举我们的选举尝试以及实际处理选票的地方
election our attempt for the election
and where we actually process the votes
在这种情况下，我们正在投票支持其他一些事情
some other things are happening input in
this case we're actually voting for
中间有其他人，所以我们不再在第一学期以为我们
someone else in between and so we're no
longer on term 1 where we thought we
开始选举，我们现在是第二学期，所以我们只需要仔细检查一下
started the election we're now on term 2
and so we just need a double check that
因为我们在执行RPC调用时没有锁，这是
because we don't have the lock while
we're performing the RPC calls which is
由于其自身的原因很重要，现在某些事情可能已经改变，我们需要
important for its own reasons now some
things might have changed and we need to
当我们将自己设置为
double check that what we assume is true
when we're setting ourselves to the
领导者仍然是真实的，因此有一种解决方法，有几种不同的方法
leader is still true so one way to solve
this that there's a few different ways
喜欢解决这个问题，就像您可以想象不投票给别人
like to solve this like you could
imagine not voting for others while
我们正在尝试选举，但在这种情况下，最简单的
we're in the middle of attempting an
election but in this case the simplest
至少在此实现中解决此问题的方法是仔细检查
way to solve this at least in this
implementation is to just double check
我们仍然处于同一任期，我们仍然是我们没有的候选人
that we're still on the same term and
we're still a candidate we haven't
恢复为关注者，所以实际上我想向您展示的一件事是
reverted to a follower so actually one
thing I want to show you is if we do
在这里打印出我们的状态，然后我们确实看到服务器0成为关注者，但是
print out our state over here then we do
see that server 0 became a follower but
它仍然是这条线上的领导者
it's still setting itself to a leader on
this line
所以是的，我们可以检查一下，如果我们不是候选人或当前
so yeah we can just check for that if
we're not a candidate or the current
任期与我们开始选举的任期不符，那么我们就
term doesn't match the term which we
started the election then let's just
退出，如果我们这样做，那么每个人都将成为领导者，我们
quit and if we do that then
so everyone becomes a leader and we
永远不要停止超过零成为领导者，所以问题解决了任何问题，是的
never cease over zero become leader so
the problem solved any question yeah
是的，我想我会的，因为如果该词是
yeah I think I think that would I
because we would not if the term is
现在比实际上更高，这可能还不够，因为我们可能
higher now than actually no it would it
might not be sufficient because we might
尝试了另一次选举，这取决于您的实现，但这是
have attempted another election it
depends on your implementation but it's
可能您可能曾尝试过更高的选举
possible that you could have attempted
another election on a higher term
事后我们都知道那是一回事，是的，那不是
afterwards all we know that's the same
thing right yeah it would not be
仅检查状态就足够了，但是如果您仅检查状态，我认为您是对的
sufficient to only check the state but I
think you're right if you only check the
任期，那么其他任何问题都足够了，是的，
term then it is sufficient all right any
other questions all right so yeah that's
对于这一部分，她将向您展示更多实际调试的示例
it for this part she's going to show you
some more examples of actually debugging
其中一些实施草案
some of these draft implementations
嗨，大家都能听到我吗
hi can you all hear me yeah
不是吗
is it not
好吧，所以在我的部分中，我将引导您完成我的工作，但是如果您有
okay so in my section I'm gonna walk you
through how I would be but if you have
就像您的粗略实现中的错误，所以我准备了一些百家乐
like a bug in your rough implementation
so I prepare a couple of baccara good
我只是试着引导你通过它，所以首先我要面对我
and I just try to walk you through it so
first I'm gonna go into my face
Bucky的实现，如果我在这里运行测试，那么对于这一点，它不会
Bucky implementation and if I run the
test here so for this one it doesn't
打印任何刚开始的东西，它将永远在这里，让我们
print anything it just gets started and
it's gonna be here forever and let's
假设我不知道为什么会发生
assume that I have no idea why there's
happening
我想发现的第一件事是它从哪里开始，我们
the first thing that I want to find out
is where it gets started and we we do
对于printf有一个很好的工具，但是如果要转到停止代码中
have a good tool for that which printf
but in the stop code if you go to
youtube go我们有一个名为printf的函数，这只是一个不错的包装器
youtube go we have a function called the
printf this is just a nice wrapper
调试器能够启用或禁用
around the block cleaners with the
debugger able to enable or disable the
锁定消息，以便启用该功能，然后返回到我的图表，这样
locking messages so I'm gonna enable
that and go back to my graph okay so
首先，当我什么时候有什么事情发生时，我
first of all when i when when there
there's something that's but happening I
总是去检查代码是否真的初始化了图形服务器，所以这里
always go check if the code actually
actually initialize graph server so here
我就打扫
I'll just clean
好吧，所以如果我再次运行测试，那么现在我知道有三个
okay so here if I run the test again
then now I know that there are three
神初始化的服务器，所以这个文件还可以，但是好像没有地方
servers that God he initialized so this
files is okay but like there's nowhere
弓在哪里发生，所以我会更深入地了解引擎盖
where the bow is happening so I'll just
go deeper into the hood just to find
它卡住了，所以现在如果您看到代码，我们称领导者为a
where it gets stuck so now if you see
the code we are calling the leader a
技术选举，所以我要去做那个功能，只是为了让我更快
tech election so I'm gonna go to that
function and just to make faster I'll
尝试检查是否开始一些迭代
try to check if it kicks off some
iteration
那部分还好，所以我们现在尝试在这里进行选举，我将
that part still fine so we we try to go
for now here we are in the election I'll
看看是否存在，因此我们实际上将请求语音发送到其他一些服务器
see if there's so we actually send the
request voice to some other servers
现在我们有点想知道客人在哪里，因为这不是
now we kind of have like more idea of
where guests are because it's not
打印一些遗憾的开始选举没有发送请求
printing that some sorry that kicks off
the election are not sending the request
这样的话，所以我会回去给她看一下我一直在尝试的客户
words so I would go back for her just to
see where customers like I always tried
如果我们调用某些函数aye-aye，则为此处
here prin if if we call some function
aye-aye
如果它确实进入了功能，我总是会抖抖，所以现在我要
I was always double shake if it actually
go into the function so now I'm going to
说这项服务是在选举开始时
say that this service is at the start of
the election
这样行得通，所以现在我们有了一个想法，就像盒子应该在这里和
and that works so now we have an idea of
like the box should be between here and
在这里，所以我们试图最小化导致错误的代码范围
here so we are trying to minimize the
scope of the code that's causing the bug
假设我在这里钉东西
let's say if I pin something here
它确实没有到达那里，所以我将其向上移动，假设这里仍然没有
and it does it doesn't get there so I
move it up let's say here still not
那里
there
现在它在那里了，所以这个功能可能有错误，我去检查一下
now it's there so the bug is probably in
this function and I just go check so
这里的问题是我试图获取我实际拥有的锁
here the problem is that I'm trying to
acquire a lock where I actually do have
锁，这将是一天的时间，所以这就是我将找到他们的第一个错误的方式
the lock so it's gonna be a day long so
that's how I will find their first bug
使用D打印机，使用printf很好，因为您可以
using the D printers and it's it's nice
to use the printf because you can like
只需关闭调试打印，并在我们的审核中获得良好的测试输出
just turn off the debugging print and
have a nice test output with our audit
调试是否需要它，这就是我将其使用得足够深以尝试喜欢的方式
debugging if you want it so that's how I
would use it deep enough to try to like
处理代码中的错误，对于此示例，实际上还有另一个技巧
handle a bug in your code and for this
example there's actually another trick
帮助您找到这种死锁，因此，如果您按Ctrl +反斜杠，您可以
to help you find this kind of deadlock
so if you press ctrl + backslash you can
看到在瓶子里，但是我按下左键就像控制和反斜杠一样
see in the bottle but bottom left that I
press like control and backslash this
该命令今天将发出退出信号
this command will send a signal quit
today
进入程序，默认情况下它将处理测验信号并退出所有程序
go program and by default it will
handles the the quiz signal and quit all
go例程和打印音频达到了堆栈速率，所以现在像Chico
the go routines and print audio strike
the stack rates so now this like Chico
像这样被碰到这里，然后会有一对
up here like this way it gets touched
and then there are gonna be a couple
在这里打印功能
functions printing here
只是试图通过所有的痕迹
just trying to go through all the traces
是的，因此实际上表明导致问题的功能是
yes so it's actually showing that the
function that's causing the problem is
求职者的封面，所以这是您必须找出另一天的权重
the cover to candidate so that's another
weight you've to find out where the day
锁是我可以删除所有这一切
locks are I can remove all this
现在它起作用了，所以这是我要讲的第二个例子
and now it works so that's the first
example that I want to go through second
在提交实验室之前，您想要做的事情是
thing that you want it you want to do
before you submit your labs is to turn
当您进行测试时，种族标志会打开
the race
flag on when you do the test the way to
这样做只是为了增加-赛前-腹股沟，在这里，因为我的工具
do that is just to add - race before
- groin and here because my implement
实施没有任何研究，所以它不会告诉你任何事情
implementation doesn't have any research
so it's not going to tell you anything
但是请注意这一点，因为它不能证明您没有
but this just be careful about this
because it's not a proof that you don't
真的有什么是它无法为您检测到种族我将要跑步
have any really it's just that it cannot
detect races for you I'm going to run
再次使用相同的命令并带有红色标记，但是现在这实际上有风险
在我的实现中进行，所以会大吼大叫您
going on in my implementation so it's
gonna yell at you that there's some
代码中的交付
deliveries going on in your code
我退出了，让我们看看警告有多么有用，所以我要
I'm quitting that and let's see like how
useful is the warning are so I'm gonna
转到我的第二个实现
go to my second implementation with
罗斯科（Rothko）和这里
Rothko and here
让我们看一下这场比赛，它告诉我们在比赛进行中
let's look at this race so it's telling
us that there's a wheat going on at the
103行，我要去那行，所以
line
103 I'm going to that line so this the
大概在星期四这里有小麦，还有一条正确的线12
wheat on probably Thursday here and
there's also a right line for 12 which
是星期四吗
is Thursday so
我要再次进入这条线，现在我们有点知道
I'm going to this line again
and now we kind of know that this this
辐射受到锁的保护，因此风险飞快地要我们和
radiation is protected by a lock so the
risk flies actually wanting us and
帮助我们找出答案，但是在这个数据库上，我们有了假货
helping us to find out but on on this
database that we have so the fake it's
只需将其锁定并解锁即可解决问题
gonna be just you lock this and unlock
it and that should solve the problem
所以在这个地方，我们有点知道如何进行基本的调试
so at this place we kind of know how to
basic like do some basic debugging does
任何人都有任何问题，不好吧，所以我要去第三个
anyone have any question no okay yeah so
I'm going to go to the third one which
我将要测试运行情况将更加困难
is going to be more difficult to find
about I'm going to test the run the
中心，现在我实际上已经有一些调试消息了
centers and now I am I actually have
some debugging messages in there already
只是看到我还有一条带有测试动作的调试消息
and just see that I also have a
debugging message with the test action
如果您参加考试，可能需要考虑做一些事情
there's something you might want to
consider doing if you go into the test
夹在这里
clip here
您可以看到测试将如何运行，然后执行一些操作
you can just see how the test would run
and then there are some actions that the
测试剪辑将使您的代码失败，通常这样做是一个好主意
test clip is gonna do to make your code
fail and it's usually a good idea to
打印出实际调试消息中该操作发生的位置，以便您
print out where that action is happening
in your actual debugging message so you
可以猜测正在发生的情况，例如在哪个阶段发生错误
can guess what is happening like where
the bug is happening in which phase of
测试是否有意义，所以现在好像我在第一种情况下做得很好
the test if that make sense so now it's
like I was doing fine in the first case
我通过了我通过了失败，但是我使他们的第二层失败了，在这里
I passed I passed the fail but I'm
failing their second tiers and here the
测试部分要找到一个，所以我要通过此测试，直到
Test section is to found one as a little
one so I'm passing this the test until
这个，如果你去的话，我实际上一直在等到领导者两个重新加入为止
this and if you go to I'm actually
passing until the leader two rejoins so
这可以使您对测试的工作方式有一个很好的了解，并且可以帮助您
this can give you a nice idea of how the
test is working and just to help you
有一个更好的例子，因为束缚在您的代码中，所以现在让我们看一下
have a better case as where the bondage
is in your code so now let's look at the
调试信息
debugging messages
所以至少当我们参加礼仪仪式时，它变成了追随者，我们
so it's least it seems like when liturgy
we joined it becomes a follower and we
有一个新的领导者，对我来说看起来不错，我们可能
have a new leader
so that looks fine to me and we probably
需要更多的调试消息，而不仅仅是它们的状态更改，所以我要
need more debugging messages instead of
just their state changes so I am going
再加上我的第一种情况，即当一个人成为领导者时
to add some more my first case that when
one becomes a leader it might not be
做你应该正确做的领导者，这样我们就被卡住了
doing what a leader should you correctly
so we got stuck
所以您可能会在我们覆盖它之后，因为最终我有了一个例行检查程序
so you might could after we cover it as
eventually there I have a go routine
呼叫操作负责人，那里只有站立习惯CD
call operate leader
there's just standing habit CD all set
到音频服务器，所以我要在这里打印一些东西说高兴-欢呼
to the audio servers so I'm gonna print
some stuff here saying happy - cheers
远
away
为了变得稳定，它将第一个快乐发送给每台服务器，还有一个仍然
so to become solidary it sends the the
first happy to each server and one still
试图给新领导者带来快乐
tries to send happy to the new leader
然后一个人成为追随者，所以现在看来​​这不是问题
and then one becomes a follower so this
doesn't look like to be a problem now
我要检查其他服务是否正确习惯了
I'm gonna check if the other service
receive habit correctly
它正在消失，我试图完成这一点，所以要成为领导者
it's taking away with I'm trying to
finish this yeah so to becomes a leader
发送高价，但没人收到习惯表格-所以如果我去同一个
to sends high bid but no one receive a
habit form - so if I go to the same
我实际上是在RPC大厅持有法律的观点树，这就是
opinion tree I actually hold the law to
the RPC Hall which is the problem that
Fabian在上一节中进行了讨论，这就是我需要解决的问题
Fabian went to in the last section so
that's that's the problem that I need to
解决，所以我应该在这里做很多
fix so what I should do is to a lot here
接着
and then
再次锁定在这里，那应该工作
lock again here and that should work
我们通过，然后在测试时可能需要做几件事
we pass and then there are couple things
that you might want to do when you test
您的粗略实现，因此实际上是在其中运行测试的脚本
your rough implementation so that's
actually script to run the test in
帝国，我可以向您展示如何使用该蠕变
imperial and I can show you how I how we
can use how we can use it this creep is
在内部同伴的支持下，有人对此提出了意见，这就是我们
in the inner peer support some someone
make a point about it and here's how we
可以使用该脚本，因此您可以在运行脚本时指定测试编号
can use the script so you run the script
specify the number of the test
我个人确实很喜欢1000，但这取决于您的喜好
personally I do like a 1000 but that
depends on your preference this is the
您想同时运行测试的课程数量，然后是
number of course that you wanna run the
test at the same time and then here's
测试，如果您运行脚本，则
the test and if you run the script then
如果您向您证明这就像我们已经运行了四个测试，那么到目前为止，所有测试都工作正常
if you show you that's like we have run
four tests so far all are working fine
它会一直这样下去，这就是我调试的方式
and it's gonna keep going like that so
that's how I would go about debugging
粗略的实施，欢迎您在上班时间上班
rough implementation and you are all
welcome to come to office hours when you
需要帮忙
need help